Okay, the toss, the purpose of the toss is to get the ball in good position so you can hit the serve.
So if I toss the ball way over my head, I'm not going to be able to hit that serve very comfortably.
So you want to learn to toss it right up there so you can hit the ball consistently.
Take any other sport, if you watch golfers, they're going to line the ball up where they can hit it.
So in tennis you want to get the toss right where you can hit it comfortably for the serve that you want to hit.
Now the toss looks pretty easy to the casual player, which is why nobody ever practices it.
But if you practice your toss just a little bit, your toss will improve, and when your toss improves, guess what?
Your serve improves, because it's a lot easier to hit the ball right there every time than it is, one time over there, one time over there.
So what I've done is I've rigged up a little practice device on the fence here.
This is just a hanger.
You can go and get a little basket or whatever.
But what I want people to do, you just take a ball, and you just toss it through the hoop, which isn't as easy as it looks even for somebody that has practiced as much as me.
It still isn't that easy.
So you want to just practice like that, or you can come out here and just try to make a basket.
So if you do this, your toss will improve dramatically.
There's a lot more technical issues with the toss, but if you just start with learning to toss it up into a target, you'll be amazed at how quickly your toss improves, and your serve.